# **Karthik Padav**

karthikpadav@gmail.com https://karthikpadav.vercel.app linkedin.com/in/karthik-padav +91 9901373620

I'm a Software Developer with over 8 years of experience, Specialising in React.js. I enjoy creating user-friendly solutions and have a background in both Front-End and Back-End development. Whether it's building dynamic web applications or mobile solutions with React Native, I bring a passion for clean code and effective design to every project.

#### **SKILLS**

JavaScript, React js, Redux toolkit, Redux thunk, Next js, Vue js, Ionic-v1, Tailwind CSS, Material UI, Bootstrap, Ant design, CSS3, HTML5, JQuery, Photoshop, Node js, Express, React Native, Socket.io, Angular js and WordPress

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Luxoft**, Bangalore — Senior Software Engineer

JANUARY 2023 - PRESENT

- High-performance application built using ReactJs v18, reduxjs/toolkit with redux thunk, React Hooks, Custom Hooks, React-Router, JavaScript, Ant design, and Formik
- Develop and maintain stable codebases.
- Conduct bug fixes and participate in code reviews.
- Ensure comprehensive documentation and reporting throughout the development lifecycle.
- Code merging and building/deploying the code to the central server.
- Agile Methodologies for incremental development to deliver better applications

## **Tecnotree**, Bangalore — Senior Software Engineer

NOVEMBER 2019 - JANUARY 2023

- Developed high-performance application using ReactJs, Redux, React Hooks, React-Router, JavaScript, Html5, Material UI, and Formik
- Use of react-jsonschema-form to create A simple React component capable of using JSON Schema to declaratively build and customise web forms.
- Built reusable custom components for UX-library consisting of Accordion, Filters, DropDown, Modal PopUp, and Icons.
- Maintained high-level expertise in React state management strategies including Redux, and Redux Persist.
- Exclusively used React-Hooks to handle application life-cycle processes.
- Worked in Agile Methodologies for incremental development to deliver better applications

## **The Fuller Life**, Bangalore — Front-End developer

OCTOBER 2017 - AUGUST 2019

- Implemented a mobile-first approach to existing websites.
- Worked on several Health and wellness, and employee engagement websites using Vue js, React js, Redux, HTML5, Bootstrap, and Bulma
- Designing and implementing HTML email templates and newsletters for marketing campaigns.

## **Codecraft Technologies**, Bangalore — Front-End developer

MARCH 2016 - OCTOBER 2017

- Designed dynamic and multi-browser compatible web pages using HTML, CSS, Angular
- Communication-Timeline application about all Creative experiences between Creator and User/Fan using IONIC v1
- Dashboard for survey app using Angular, Bootstrap
- An application that helps you to book an ambulance during the time of a medical emergency using Template7 and JQuery
- Worked on the E-commerce website and on several Real Estate websites using HTML5 and Bootstrap

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

# React Native - The Practical Guide

Complete NodeJS Developer (GraphQL, MongoDB, + more)

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor Of Engineering In Computer Science**

2012 - 2015

Shree Devi Institute of Technology, Mangalore (VTU, Belgaum)

## **Diploma In Computer Science**

2009 - 2012

P.A Polytechnic (DTE, Karnataka)

#### **DEMO PROJECTS**

#### **Movies And TV Shows**

React js, Next js, Material UI
List of all new Movies and TV
shows with ratings and reviews.
All contents are fetched from
TMDB

# <u>Did You Know? - Facts</u> <u>Unlimited</u>

React Native

Option to share interesting facts among your friends and families or on other social media.

#### The Color Picker

React js, Next js, Tailwind CSS Color patterns inspired by thousands of beautiful color schemes.

### <u>Instagram downloader</u>

React Native

Android app that helps you download Instagram Videos, Photos, IGTV & albums.

# <u>All India pin code directory</u>

React Native

This Application allows users to get Post Office details by searching Postal PIN Code or Post Office Branch Name.

## **HD Gaming wallpaper**

React Native

HD Gaming wallpaper is an Android app with a collection of wallpapers.